Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
Paul B. MacCready Papers
1931-2002
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
MacCready, Paul B. (Paul Beattie) (Aeronautical Engineer)
MacCreadyPB
56.5 linear feet (113 archival boxes)
Arriving on December 30th 2003, the collection documents most aspects of MacCready's career and many features of his individual character. Constituted within the papers is a diverse array of documents, media, objects, manuscripts and printed material; awards; videos and film; photographs and slides, diaries and notebooks; memorabilia, biographical material and ephemera. While the collection spans over seventy years (ca. 1930-2002), the bulk of material dates from the mid 1960s to the mid '90s. Especially prevalent within the collection are papers and ephemera from 1977 to 1985 during which time MacCready was working on his Gossamers and interest in human-powered flight was at its peak
Access
The collection is open for research. The collection has been mostly digitized and is available online. The physical collection is STORED OFFSITE. Researchers must contact the Archives at least 72 hours in advance for access.
Acquisition Information
The Papers of Paul B. MacCready were donated to the Caltech Archives in December 2003.
Biography
Paul B. MacCready, Jr. (September 29, 1925 - August 28, 2007) was an American aeronautical engineer, entrepreneur and inventor. He was the founder of Meteorology Research, Inc., and AeroVironment. He was the designer of the human-powered aircrafts Gossamer Condor and Gossamer Albatross, both winning the Kremer prize, respectively in 1977 and 1979. To top off his successes, MacCready's Bionic Bat - an aircraft that used human power not only to power the aircraft directly, but to store energy in a battery - won yet another two Kremer Prize for human-powered air speed. In addition to these achievements, MacCready designed and produced the Gossamer Penguin, the first airplane to be completely solar powered. He also created the Solar Challenger, a similar aircraft used to spark the public imagination concerning the possibilities of solar power. Yet MacCready was not limited to the development of exceptional flying machines. His interest in the environment and technology led him to construct other kinds of innovative machinery. Notably, in 1987 he helped build the solar powered Sunraycer which won the World Solar Challenge race across Australia. In collaboration with General Motors, he developed the aerodynamically efficient electric powered car, called Impact. Paul MacCready was the recipient of many awards. Amongst the countless honorary degrees, prizes, medals and decorations, the American Society of Mechanical Engineers named him "Engineer of the Century" in 1978 and bestowed upon him the Ralph Coats Roe Medal in 1998 for bettering the public's appreciation of engineering. In 1981 he was named the "Inventor of the Year" and in 1982 he received the prestigious Lindbergh Award. He received the Howard Hughes Memorial Award for lifetime achievement (1999) and the Design News Special Achievement Award. In 1999 he was included in Time magazine's "The Century's Greatest Minds" and also inducted into the Aviation Hall of Fame. He received the Guggenheim medal in 1987, the Caltech Distinguished Alumni Award in 1978, the AIAA Reed Aeronautical Award in 1979 and many other accolades. The Smithsonian National Air Space Museum displays five vehicles designed by Paul MacCready.
Scope and Contents
The Paul B. MacCready Papers include documents, media, objects, manuscripts and printed material; awards; videos and film; photographs and slides, diaries and notebooks; memorabilia, biographical material and ephemera.
Related Material
The Gell-Mann papers include papers and correspondence between Gell-Mann and MacCready
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 7 series. Some of the major projects where MacCready was the main player, like the Gossamer Condor and Gossamer Albatross are covered in more than one series, in the case of videos, audios and images are grouped by their media.
Series 1, AeroVironment includes papers and correspondence related to activities, projects, collaborations and inventions taken place during the years from the foundation of AeroVironment in 1971 to 2002. Papers are arranged chronologically within a subseries or a header. Additional papers and other media related to work done during this period span can be found throughout the collection. The series is subdivided into 9 subseries: Subseries 1: AeroVironment history and strategic planning. Subseries 2: meetings, conferences, talks and visits. Subseries 3: Memos, business documents and correspondence. Subseries 4: Patents and Trademarks. Subseries 5: Gossamer Condor. Subseries 6: Gossamer Albatross. Subseries 7: Solar powered aircrafts. Subseries 8: General Motors including EV1 and GM Sunraycer. Subseries 9: Other AV projects.
Series 2, Diaries includes mostly diaries and a few appointments calendars and address books, arranged chronologically from 1951 to 1999. The bulk of the diaries are from 1951 to 1974.
Series 3, Notebooks includes notebooks starting from the Meteorology period from 1961 until December 2002. The notebooks include annotations about daily appointments and activities, replacing the use of diaries and calendars, addresses, business cards stapled to pages and many technical notes.
Series 4, Writings includes articles, talks and conference presentations. The papers are arranged chronologically and they span from 1945 to 2002.
Series 5, Biographical and correspondence consists of five subseries. Subseries 1 includes mostly personal correspondence, from 1943 to 2000, with the bulk of it covering the 1940s. Subseries 2 covers school and university years. Subseries 3 includes papers, certificates, trophies and other material related to the many awards that Paul MacCready received during his working life. Subseries 4 includes miscellaneous papers and memorabilia. Subseries 5 includes the many articles that were written in magazines, journals and other publications about MacCready and his projects. Many of these articles were published in foreign publications.
Series 6, Miscellaneous material consists of four subseries. Subseries 1 includes papers about MacCready's first company, Meteorology Research Inc., from 1953 to 1972. Subseries 2 covers soaring and gliding. Subseries 3 includes papers related to MacCready's involvement in educational programs and Subseries 4 includes miscellaneous papers and other project.
Series 7, Still images and A-V includes photos, slides, videos and audios.
Aeronautics; Drone aircraft; Human powered aircraft; Meteorology; Renewable energy sources; Solar energy; Solar planes; Aeronautical engineers; Inventors
- AeroVironment, 1
  - AeroVironment history and strategic planning, 1
    - AV Christmas cards, undated; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_01 (Box 1.1, Folder 1)
    - AV plan for development, 1971 July 26; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_02 (Box 1.1, Folder 2)
    - AV leaflets and publications, 1973-2001; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_03 (Box 1.1, Folder 3)
    - AV history, 1981; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_04 (Box 1.1, Folder 4)
    - AV strategic business and organizational plans, 1983-1997; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_05 (Box 1.1, Folder 5)
    - AV overview of activities, 1986; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_06 (Box 1.1, Folder 6)
    - AV strategic and business plans, 1994-1997; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_07 (Box 1.1, Folder 7)
    - Educational strategies, 1995; MacCreadyPB_01_01_001_08 (Box 1.1, Folder 8)
  - Meetings, conferences, talks and visits, 2
    - Third International Human Powered Vehicle Scientific Symposium (Expo 86; Vancouver, Canada), 1986 August 24-31; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_01 (Box 1.2, Folder 1)
    - Gossamer Albatross 10th anniversary of the cross-channel flight, 1989 June 10; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_02 (Box 1.2, Folder 2)
    - Air toxics workshop, 1989 June 15; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_03 (Box 1.2, Folder 3)
    - An evolutionary perspective (a talk at the Free Inquiry conference; San Francisco), 1989 July 27-30; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_04 (Box 1.2, Folder 4)
    - Aerodynamics of low-powered vehicles (German Soaring Convention, Hamburg), 1989 November 4-5; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_05 (Box 1.2, Folder 5)
    - 1990 World Solar Challenge (Australia), 1990 November; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_06 (Box 1.2, Folder 6)
    - Perspectives on the Future (Caltech), 1990 November 14-15; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_07 (Box 1.2, Folder 7)
    - Caltech Industrial Associates' Research Directors conference, 1991 January 29-30; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_08 (Box 1.2, Folder 8)
    - Regulations vs the Free Market, 1991 February 23; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_09 (Box 1.2, Folder 9)
    - The Environmental and Energy Study Institute event, 1991 February 27; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_10 (Box 1.2, Folder 10)
    - US Air Force, Space Systems division, 1991 April 2; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_11 (Box 1.2, Folder 11)
    - Chevron Research and Technology Company, 1991 May 16; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_12 (Box 1.2, Folder 12)
    - JASON summer study: small satellites and RPVs, 1991 June 18-21; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_13 (Box 1.2, Folder 13)
    - Comments regarding the high altitude technologies for ARM discussed at Jason meetings (La Jolla, California), 1991 June 20-21; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_14 (Box 1.2, Folder 14)
    - A decade of new car technology, 1991 November 1; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_15 (Box 1.2, Folder 15)
    - Environmental Business 92: West conference, 1992; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_16 (Box 1.2, Folder 16)
    - Department of Energy workshop on fuel cells, 1992 January 7-8; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_17 (Box 1.2, Folder 17)
    - The future of the electric car: a special science and society program (Executive Forum, Caltech), 1992 April 20; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_18 (Box 1.2, Folder 18)
    - Pasadena Art Center, 1992 May 19; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_19 (Box 1.2, Folder 19)
    - The electric car in perspective (Electric vehicle showcase session: Markets and production panel. Wescon), 1992 November 17; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_20 (Box 1.2, Folder 20)
    - Research topics in advanced electric and hybrid propulsion (DARPA electric, hybrid, and natural gas engine workshop), 1992 December 15; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_21 (Box 1.2, Folder 21)
    - Electric Vehicle Task Force, 1993 February 2; MacCreadyPB_01_02_002_22 (Box 1.2, Folder 22)
    - The electric vehicle and the American community: a national planning and design competition, 1993 April 21-22; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_01 (Box 1.3, Folder 1)
    - Jumpstart: a workshop focused on the Sub-Car Electric Vehicle Opportunity, 1993 June 2; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_02 (Box 1.3, Folder 2)
    - Sunrayce 93 (Texas), 1993 June 16-26; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_03 (Box 1.3, Folder 3)
    - The electric vehicle and the American community: a workshop on a future infrastructure, 1993 June 18; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_04 (Box 1.3, Folder 4)
    - First Annual World Car 2001 Conference, 1993 June 20-24; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_05 (Box 1.3, Folder 5)
    - 19th Annual international human powered speed championship, 1993 August 14-15; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_06 (Box 1.3, Folder 6)
    - 21st Century Transportation: Challenges and Opportunities (Southern California - Nevada Section of the Electrochemical Society), 1993 October 20; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_07 (Box 1.3, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Business 93: West conference, 1993 October 26; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_08 (Box 1.3, Folder 8)
    - Mobile Sources and the Clean Air Act: Coax, Quantity, Cure (HazMat West, 1993), 1993 November 17; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_09 (Box 1.3, Folder 9)
    - Hawaii Electric Vehicle conference, 1993 December 9-10; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_10 (Box 1.3, Folder 10)
    - Zero Emission Vehicle technical meeting, 1994 January 25-26; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_11 (Box 1.3, Folder 11)
    - National Institute of Standards and Technology staff colloquium, 1994 January 28; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_12 (Box 1.3, Folder 12)
    - Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory - Distinguished Lecture Series, 1994 February 22; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_13 (Box 1.3, Folder 13)
    - Exploratorium event, 1994 September 6; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_14 (Box 1.3, Folder 14)
    - Benefiting change (Engineering Lecture Series, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory), 1995 March 23; MacCreadyPB_01_02_003_15 (Box 1.3, Folder 15)
    - Energy, environment and public policy (Annual Conference of the American Society for Engineering Education), 1995 June 28; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_01 (Box 1.4, Folder 1)
    - Caltech Y talk, 1995 July 8; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_02 (Box 1.4, Folder 2)
    - Apple Hill Learning Lab, 1995 August 28 - September 1; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_03 (Box 1.4, Folder 3)
    - Honda R & D conference, 1995 September 15; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_04 (Box 1.4, Folder 4)
    - The Caltech precollege science initiative, 1995 October 5; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_05 (Box 1.4, Folder 5)
    - Eliot Middle School, 1995 October 11; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_06 (Box 1.4, Folder 6)
    - Electric Vehicle EduFaire at the Alfred B. Nobel Middle School (Northridge, California), 1996 June 6; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_07 (Box 1.4, Folder 7)
    - AV and Saturn of Monrovia electric vehicle exhibit and barbecue, 1996 June 8; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_08 (Box 1.4, Folder 8)
    - ITS-Davis Board of Advisors meeting, 1996 September 20; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_09 (Box 1.4, Folder 9)
    - Gossamer Condor 20th year reunion, 1997 August 23; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_10 (Box 1.4, Folder 10)
    - MEMS PI meeting (Seattle, WA), 1998 January 14-16; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_11 (Box 1.4, Folder 11)
    - AVES farewell lunch, 1998 August 27; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_12 (Box 1.4, Folder 12)
    - IEEE Spectrum EV Roundtable - Engineering the EV future (Caltech), 1998 September 3; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_13 (Box 1.4, Folder 13)
    - NRC/TRB Workshop on Enabling Transportation Research (National Research Council; Washington, D.C.), 1998 September 9-10; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_14 (Box 1.4, Folder 14)
    - New Mobility: a ITS UC Davis workshop, 1998 November 2; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_15 (Box 1.4, Folder 15)
    - Centurian open house (NASA Dryden), 1998 December 19; MacCreadyPB_01_02_004_16 (Box 1.4, Folder 16)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      This file has not been digitized.
    - National Renewal Energy Laboratory (Denver, CO), 1999 January 25; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_01 (Box 1.5, Folder 1)
    - Soaring: Addictions and perspectives (Presentation at the SSA Soaring Convention, Knoxville, TN), 1999 February 27; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_02 (Box 1.5, Folder 2)
    - MAV, 1999 April 26-27; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_03 (Box 1.5, Folder 3)
    - DARPA, 1999 August 25; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_04 (Box 1.5, Folder 4)
    - School visits, 2000; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_05 (Box 1.5, Folder 5)
    - Douglas C. Kruse (Micro-Pulse Controls, Inc.), 2000 March 20; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_06 (Box 1.5, Folder 6)
    - Delco Remy visit, 2000 March 21; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_07 (Box 1.5, Folder 7)
    - Frank Fernandez (DARPA), 2000 May 24; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_08 (Box 1.5, Folder 8)
    - Continental and Delco Remy America visit, 2000 September 7-9; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_09 (Box 1.5, Folder 9)
    - International symposium on fuel cells for vehicles (Nagoya, Japan), 2000 November 20-22; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_10 (Box 1.5, Folder 10)
    - The Transportation Vision 2050 (Memphis, Tennessee), 2000 November 30 - December 1; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_11 (Box 1.5, Folder 11)
    - Nicholas P. Jensen (NyPa International) visit, 2001 October 25; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_12 (Box 1.5, Folder 12)
    - Distributed Energy Outlook conference, 2001 November 12-14; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_13 (Box 1.5, Folder 13)
    - Autonomous vehicles: innovation, opportunity, responsibility (IDC conference. Adelaide, Australia), 2002 February 11-13; MacCreadyPB_01_02_005_14 (Box 1.5, Folder 14)
  - Memos, business documents and correspondence, 3
    - Lecture 1-1: introduction, background and overview by Paul MacCready of Aerovironment, undated; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_15 (Box 1.5, Folder 15)
    - Proposal for the ultra light maximum performance airplane, undated; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_16 (Box 1.5, Folder 16)
    - The power required for lift, undated; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_17 (Box 1.5, Folder 17)
    - Fuel economy, 1980; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_18 (Box 1.5, Folder 18)
    - The Gossamer Condor and Albatross: a case study in aircraft design, 1980 June 16; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_19 (Box 1.5, Folder 19)
    - Solar powered aircraft, 1980 November 1; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_20 (Box 1.5, Folder 20)
    - Falcon flyer, 1981; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_21 (Box 1.5, Folder 21)
    - Available watts, 1981 June 19; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_22 (Box 1.5, Folder 22)
    - Stability and control of the Gossamer human-powered aircraft by analysis and flight test (NASA Contractor Report 3627), 1982 October; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_23 (Box 1.5, Folder 23)
    - Program plan for development of a two-place ultralight aircraft, 1983 November; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_24 (Box 1.5, Folder 24)
    - Lightweight advanced technology aircraft, 1984 April; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_25 (Box 1.5, Folder 25)
    - Energy apparatus, 1985 August 24; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_26 (Box 1.5, Folder 26)
    - Biological flight, airplane flight, 1985 October; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_27 (Box 1.5, Folder 27)
    - HiLine Project, 1985-1989; MacCreadyPB_01_03_005_28 (Box 1.5, Folder 28)
    - Apple computers and human powered vehicles, 1986; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_01 (Box 1.6, Folder 1)
    - Flapping wing propulsion, 1986 April; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_02 (Box 1.6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence folder 1, 1986-1989; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_03 (Box 1.6, Folder 3)
    - Aluminum batteries, 1988; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_04 (Box 1.6, Folder 4)
    - Assessment of solar-power for cars, 1989; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_05 (Box 1.6, Folder 5)
    - Paper cuttings on electric cars technology, 1989-1990; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_06 (Box 1.6, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1989-1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_07 (Box 1.6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence folder 2, 1990; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_08 (Box 1.6, Folder 8)
    - Hybrids, 1990 January 30; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_09 (Box 1.6, Folder 9)
    - Raptor/Talon Program, 1990-1992; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_10 (Box 1.6, Folder 10)
    - Air Resources Board proposal, 1991; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_11 (Box 1.6, Folder 11)
    - Hearing of the Subcommittee on toxic substances, environmental oversight, research and development committee on environment and public works, 1991; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_12 (Box 1.6, Folder 12)
    - Comments on energy, environment, economics and regulation, 1991 March 27; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_13 (Box 1.6, Folder 13)
    - Perspectives on auto industry transition, 1991 April 26; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_14 (Box 1.6, Folder 14)
    - Los Angeles Harbor wind power plant, 1991 September 23; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_15 (Box 1.6, Folder 15)
    - Hybrid perspective: a memorandum, 1991 December 20; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_16 (Box 1.6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence folder 3, 1991-1992; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_17 (Box 1.6, Folder 17)
    - The global challenge logo prize, 1992; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_18 (Box 1.6, Folder 18)
    - BART and CALSTART, 1992; MacCreadyPB_01_03_006_19 (Box 1.6, Folder 19)
    - Report on the future of the automobile in the urban environment: a new approach to public policy. By Elmer W. Johnson, 1992-1993; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_01 (Box 1.7, Folder 1)
    - National Education Corporation (NEC), 1992-1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_02 (Box 1.7, Folder 2)
    - Lumsdaine, Edward, 1992-1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_03 (Box 1.7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence folder 4, 1993-1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_04 (Box 1.7, Folder 4)
    - Reports on Slipper, Power Pet and battery powered mobility systems, ca. 1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_05 (Box 1.7, Folder 5)
    - Air Resources Board - Low Emission Vehicle regulations, 1995; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_06 (Box 1.7, Folder 6)
    - Andrew Frank electric vehicles research, 1996; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_07 (Box 1.7, Folder 7)
    - Memo on Leaping, not ambling, into effective learning, 1996 October 13; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_08 (Box 1.7, Folder 8)
    - Aeronautics, Pathfinder, F-15 Active: Educators guide with activities, 1997; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_09 (Box 1.7, Folder 9)
    - De-mining program and land mine treaty, 1997; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_10 (Box 1.7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence folder 5, 1997-1998; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_11 (Box 1.7, Folder 11)
    - Helios project - DARPA, 1999; MacCreadyPB_01_03_007_12 (Box 1.7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence folder 6, 1999-2002; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_01 (Box 1.8, Folder 1)
    - Snoopy system, 2000; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_02 (Box 1.8, Folder 2)
    - Motors and batteries, 2000; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_03 (Box 1.8, Folder 3)
    - Memo on September 11, 2001 in perspective, for U.S., the future, and AV, 2001 September; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_04 (Box 1.8, Folder 4)
    - Helios aircraft and the Collier trophy, 2002; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_05 (Box 1.8, Folder 5)
    - NASA Express magazine and other documents, 2002; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_06 (Box 1.8, Folder 6)
    - Model Aviation magazine article about Paul MAcCready, 2002; MacCreadyPB_01_03_008_07 (Box 1.8, Folder 7)
  - Patents and Trademarks, 4
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 1, 1974; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_08 (Box 1.8, Folder 8)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 2, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_09 (Box 1.8, Folder 9)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 3, 1977-1978; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_10 (Box 1.8, Folder 10)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 4, 1978; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_11 (Box 1.8, Folder 11)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 5, 1978-1979; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_12 (Box 1.8, Folder 12)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 6, 1979; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_13 (Box 1.8, Folder 13)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 7, 1979; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_14 (Box 1.8, Folder 14)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 8, 1979; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_15 (Box 1.8, Folder 15)
    - Patents and Trademarks, folder 9, 1979-1980; MacCreadyPB_01_04_008_16 (Box 1.8, Folder 16)
  - Gossamer Condor, 5
    - Gossamer Condor: Kremer prize rules, correspondence and other documents, 1972-1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_01 (Box 1.9, Folder 1)
    - Gossamer Condor: Kremer prize, early design notes, 1976; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_02 (Box 1.9, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer Condor: wires and tubes, 1976; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_03 (Box 1.9, Folder 3)
    - Gossamer Condor: plastic and bicycle, 1976; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_04 (Box 1.9, Folder 4)
    - Gossamer Condor: MGM tests, 1976; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_05 (Box 1.9, Folder 5)
    - Gossamer Condor: overall design, 1976-1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_06 (Box 1.9, Folder 6)
    - Gossamer Condor: legal papers, 1976-1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_07 (Box 1.9, Folder 7)
    - Gossamer Condor: technical papers, including drawings, 1976-1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_08 (Box 1.9, Folder 8)
    - Gossamer Condor: events material and other information notes, 1976-1978; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_09 (Box 1.9, Folder 9)
    - Gossamer Condor: Shedd production movie for NOVA PBS, 1976-1978; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_10 (Box 1.9, Folder 10)
    - Gossamer Condor: history of models, 1976-1996; MacCreadyPB_01_05_009_11 (Box 1.9, Folder 11)
    - Gossamer Condor: airfoil, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_010_01 (Box 1.10, Folder 1)
    - Gossamer Condor: Shafter Airport, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_010_02 (Box 1.10, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer Condor: Dewey (Jeremy T.) Gram's writings, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_010_03 (Box 1.10, Folder 3)
    - Gossamer Condor: National Aeronautics Association, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_010_04 (Box 1.10, Folder 4)
    - Gossamer Condor: correspondence, folder 1, 1977; MacCreadyPB_01_05_010_05 (Box 1.10, Folder 5)